Guide to the Eric McKitrick papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Subseries IV: Professional and Research Activities, 1947-2001
  - Subseries IV.1: Organizations, Seminars, and Projects, 1951-2001
    - Archival Materials-MS Holdings, 1953-1966 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Franklin Mint, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Critiques of Manuscripts, 1960, 1970-2000, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Funk and Wagnall's Encyclopedia, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      (McKitrick's acted as a consultant on 19th century United States history)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1953-1962 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Fellowships-Grants-Foundations, 1951-1958, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Grant and Fellowship Proposals (All Unsuccessful), 1982-1986 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      (Includes items related to Age of Federalism)
    - Society for Historians of the Gilded Age and Progressive Area (SHGAPE), 1994-1999 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - The Gilded Age--General, 1993-1997 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Bancroft Prize
      - 1985 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - 1967, 1976, 1998, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Stanley Elkins
      - Comment on Ira Berlin [Paper] (Southern Historical Association), 1991 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - The First Emancipation (Berkeley), 1961 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IV.2: Writing Projects, 1950-2001
    consists primarily of files related to published articles or book reviews, and include correspondence, notes, and drafts. A full set of book reviews, as well as reprint copies of several published articles, are filed in Subseries 6: Publications.
    - The Hofstadter Aegis, 1972-1975 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      (Book project)
    - Review of Trefousse's Andrew Johnson, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Aaron Burr, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      (McKitrick's review of Lomask's book)
    - Henry Clay, 1984-1992 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      (Includes reprint article (1984) and correspondence related to McKitrick's review of Remini's book)
    - Book Reviews for the New York Review of Books
      - Miller, Arguing About Slavery, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - J. Ellis, American Sphinx, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Nagel, John Quincy Adams, 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Mayer, All on Fire (W.L. Garrison), 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Dalzell, George Washington's Mount Vernon, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Battle of New Orleans, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 8)
        (Request for review, only)
      - Jefferson Davis, 1999-2001 (Box 26, Folder 1)
        (Book by William Cooper)
    - The New Prudery, Undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - "Conservatism", 1959 (Box 34, Folder 9)
      (Appears to be "Conservatism Today article, 1959. Includes correspondence.)
    - Literary Musings, 1950s (Box 34, Folder 10)
      (various correspondence, "New Models for Literary Criticism" by McKitrick)
    - Political Sociology, 1963 (Box 34, Folder 11)
      ("Political Sociology and the Historian" by McKitrick)
    - Edgar Saltus (Etc.), 1950-1952 (Box 34, Folder 12)
      (Correspondence on McKitrick's article on Saltus)
    - M. Meyers and J.W. Ward on Jacksonianism, Undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Henry Adams--E. Stevenson Review-Lecture History 201, 1958-1963 (Box 34, Folder 14)
      (Includes material related to both McKitrick's book review and teaching)
    - Wilson and House, Undated (Box 34, Folder 15)
      (Handwritten notes)
    - "Prejudice", 1953-1954 (Box 34, Folder 16)
      (Includes correspondence and outline on "Prejudice as a problem for functional analysis" )
  - Subseries IV.3: Andrew Johnson and Reconstruction, 1950s-1960, 1989-1990
    includes one research file (a topical index of correspondence) and files related to reader's opinions, reviews, and the Dunning Prize.
    - Reviews of, circa 1960 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Readers' Reports-Index-Etc., 1957-1959 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Dunning Prize, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Topical Summary of Reconstruction Correspondence for Andrew Johnson and Reconstruction, circa 1950s (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Subseries IV.4: The Age of Federalism: The Early American Republic, 1788-1800, 1967-1998
    This subseries includes drafts, fan letters, reviews, research files, and files on prizes received for the book and a related symposium. The research files are extensive. These files are usually grouped together by chapter, but there are also some files on general topics. The files include correspondence with co-author Stanley Elkins, communications with research assistants, conference notes, research notes, source material, and drafts.
    There are also several annotated drafts. Each full annotated draft is in three parts and there are four copies; three copies and a "master copy." It appears that these drafts were distributed to readers for comments, but there is no clear identification of the commentator on the drafts - one full set is initialed "K.E.," another single draft has the name Ervin written on it.
    - Society of the Cincinnati, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Bancroft Prize, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Fan Letters, 1994-1997 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Reviews, circa 1993 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Williams College Symposium, 1998 September (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Full Drafts, Undated
      (There are 4 annotated draft copies of each part, including a "master copy")
      - Part 1, (4 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Part 2, (4 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Part 3, (4 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Research Files
      - America and Great Britain
        - Washington and the War Crisis 1794, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Negotiating Jay's Treaty, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Ratifying Jay's Treaty, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - The Golden Shower, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - The Populist Impulse
        - Democratic Societies--Voluntary Associations, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Whiskey Insurrection, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2 to 3)
        - Neville-Clymer Correspondence Wolcott Papers Volume XIX C.H.S., Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Retirement of Washington
        - Farewell Address, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - Monroe in Paris, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - State of Politics in 1796, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Typed Manuscripts and Miscellaneous, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - John Adams and the Dogma of Balance
        - 1. The Trouble with Adams, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - 2. Preparing for Crisis, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - 3. First Phase: The XYZ Mission, circa 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - XYZ Mission: Original MS and Paradigms, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - Fever of 1798
          - MS Draft-Paradigm-Footnotes-Miscellaneous Memos, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
          - Stan's Paradigms, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
        - Convention of 1800
          - French Archives--Reports, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
          - Convention of 1800, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
            (Manuscript)
          - Stan's Paradigms, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
          - Notes-Documents-Miscellaneous, 1986-1987, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Mentality of Federalism in 1800
        - Mentality of Federalism in 1800, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - Stan's Paradigms, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Alien Act-Fries Rebellion-Sedition, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Freedom of the Press, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Mentality of Federalism in 1800, 1981-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Original MS and Paradigm, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Modes of Thought in the Founding Generation
        - Notes, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - Paradigm-Draft-Original Typescript, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Federalists at Philadelphia and in the 1st Congress, circa 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Ch. I Modes of T & F in FG--Footnotes-Loose Ends, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
          (Includes table of contents)
      - French Revolution Calendar, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Age of Washington and Jefferson--Preliminary Ideas and Paradigms, 1966, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - George Washington, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Titles and Protocol, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Advise and Consent, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Bill of Rights, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Tariff of 1789, 1968, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Legitimacy Verified (Washington's Tour), Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Literacy, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Age of Washington and Jefferson--Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1967-1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Age of Federalism--General. Book Ads, Clippings, Etc., 1983-1985, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous Notes on Age of Washington and Jefferson, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - James Madison, 1971, Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Alexander Hamilton, 1968-1977, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - The Classical Tradition, 1973, Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - An Age of Ideology, Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Conference Notes, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Divided Mind of James Madison
        - Ch. IV Divided Mind of James Madison (Introduction), Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - Funding-Assumption-Residence, 1970, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - Theories of Culture, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Thomas Jefferson and the Yeoman Republic
        - European Cities--Paris, London, St. Petersburg., Etc., 1971-1980, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
        - New York--Culture, Etc., 1971-1980, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - Washington, D.C., 1979-1982, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - MS and Footnotes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Jefferson as Secretary of State
        - Introduction and Nootka Sound, 1971, Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
        - The Bank, 1971, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
        - Jefferson and Hammond, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Ch. VII, Emergence of Partisan Politics
        - Hamilton's Industrial Vision, 1973, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - Madison Revises "The Federalist", 1973, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - Hamilton Beleaguered, 1973, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - The Newspaper War, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Ch. VIII, The French Revolution in America
        - Investigating Hamilton, 1974, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - American and France: How Two Peoples Have Viewed Each Other, 1976, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
        - First Responses to the Revolution, 1976, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
        - Adams-Jefferson-Paine-Morris, 1976-1981, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
        - Citizen Genet and His Mission, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
        - Defining American Neutrality, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
        - Collapse of the Genet Mission, Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
        - French Revolution and Partisan Politics, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Afterthought: The View from Paris, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
        - Miscellaneous--Correspondence, Bibliography, Etc., Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
        - Naval Quasi-War--Miscellaneous Notes and Documents, 1985, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Adams and the Dogma of Balance
        - Fever of 1798
          - H.G. Otis, Pickering, McHenry, Gerry, Washington, Murray, etc., etc., Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
          - Messages to Congress, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
          - Annals, AS & Aurora-Petitions, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
          - Abigail Adams, 1983, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
        - Adams Temporizes- February-October, 1789
          - Original MS and Paradigms, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 9)
          - Letters (Box 9, Folder 1)
          - Miscellaneous Notes and Documents (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - The Naval Quasi War
        - Paradigm and Drafts; Final Typescript (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Documents, Miscellaneous Notes, etc. (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Washington D.C. and the Man of Letters: M. Twain and H. Adams, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Subseries IV.5: Speeches and Lectures, 1950s-1995
    includes files on McKitrick's radio and television appearances, lectures, and activities at professional conferences where he either presented or commented on papers. These files include correspondence, notes, drafts, and other material.
    - Lifelong Learners--Lecture, 1995 October 6 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Caseville Kiwanis, 1995 August 30 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Middlebury College (Charles Scott)--Lecture, 1995 February 22 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Smithsonian Lecture, 1993 September 30 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Manhattan College, 1990 March (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Association for Documentary Editing, 1983 October 6 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Columbia Conference on Cities, 1980 September (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Lincoln-The Politician as a Man of Words, 1978-1986, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Student Rebellion in the 1960s, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Culture and the Wilderness, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Washington: The Idea of a Capital City, 1976-1980, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Best and Worst Vice Presidents, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      (McKitrick's comments in "Columbia Today")
    - Civil War Centennial, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Richard Hofstadter: American Historian, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Frontiers of Influence, 1958, Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - American Historical Association(AHA), 1994 January (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Southern Historical Association--Commentary on M. Perman and L. Benedict, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Organization of American Historians (OAH), 1970 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Southern Historical Association--Commentary on H. Johnson and R. Ellis, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - American Historical Association (AHA)--Commentary on Pease and Shover, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Southern Historical Association, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - American Historical Association (AHA)--Commentary on C. Kenyon and R. Buel, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - American Studies Association, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Southern Historical Association, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Mississippi Valley Historical Association--Commentary on E.B. Smith, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - American Historical Association--Commentary on M. Ringold and R. Nichols, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - TV and Radio Appearances, 1962-1964 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Talks and Lectures
      - 1950s (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - 1960-1969, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - 1970s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - White House Luncheon, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - New Party System/Frontier in American History/Era of Good Feelings, Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Conference on Political Parties, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Subseries IV.6: Publications, 1947-1999
    includes a complete set of McKitrick's published book reviews (1947-1999) and reprint copies of several articles (1951-1978). The book reviews include McKitrick's reviews of juvenilia (1947-1948) and his professional reviews of works relating to American history (1954-1999).
    - Book Reviews, 1947-1999 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Reprints, 1951-1978 (Box 48, Folder 6 to 7)
- Series V: Correspondence, 1937-2001
  This series contains three sets of correspondence files: professional, alphabetical, and a small amount of personal correspondence from the 1930s-1940s.
  - Subseries V.1: Professional Correspondence, 1940s-2001
    includes correspondence on job offers, reprint permissions, and with publishers. McKitrick kept chronological files for both general professional and publisher correspondence. He also kept files on specific publishers. The files on publishers include correspondence, contracts, royalty statements, and information on McKitrick's reading and consulting projects.
    - Professional Correspondence
      - 1950s-1961 (Box 19, Folder 10 to 11)
      - 1962-1980s (Box 20, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Informal and Miscellaneous, 1940s-1960s (Box 20, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Publishers Miscellaneous
      - 1950s-1964, (2 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 9 to 10)
      - 1965-1970s, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Hill and Wang, 1966-1974 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - New York Review of Books, 1965-1996 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Columbia University Press, 1955-1979 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Oxford University Press, 1962-2001, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Harper's, 1962-1990 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Knopf, 1954-1990 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Random House, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      (Comments on Gore Vidal's 1876 manuscript)
    - American Historical Review, 1964-1993 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1959-1991 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Prentice-Hall, 1962-1972 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Time, Inc., 1962 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - American Quarterly, 1957-1972 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Political Science Quarterly, 1954-1974 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - John Wiley--Bill Gum, 1962-1969 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Harcourt, Brace, 1960-1966 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Commentary, 1959-1964 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Scott Foresman, 1964-1968 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Reprint Permissions, 1969-1986 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Job Offers, 1952, 1961-1974 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Subseries V.2: Alphabetical File, 1953-2000
    is comprised of files on both personal and professional correspondents. Many files also function as subject files; these files include correspondence not only with the named persons, but also in reference to them in relation to manuscripts, recommendations, and projects. In addition to correspondence, many files include clippings, manuscripts, and memorials prepared by McKitrick.
    Most of the correspondents in the alphabetical file are colleagues, dissertation advisees, former students, and historians, but correspondence with members of Grace Church and the Century Association is also included in the files. Important correspondents include Bishop Christopher FitzSimons Allison, Stanley Elkins, Richard Hofstadter, Elizabeth McCaughey (Ross), Lionel Trilling, C. Vann Woodward, and Mike Wallace (co-author of Gotham: A History of New York City to 1898).
    - Allison, Fitz, circa 1988-2000 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      (Bishop Christopher FitzSimons Allison)
    - Banner, L & J, 1973-1984 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Basen, Neil, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Beisner, Bob, 1960-1977 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Ben-Atar, Doron, 1990-1998 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Bender, Tom, 1979-1987 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Blanton, Walker, 1961-1971 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Brandeis: Levy-Meyers-Roche, 1962-1965 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Brock, William, 1961-1986 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Brown, Tom, 1978-1981 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Burton, Ann, 1976-2000 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Burrows, Ed, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Chadwick, Owen, 1974-1991 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Chatfield, Jack, 1982-1996 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Copley, Susan & David, 1994-1999 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Cornog, Evan, 1989-2001 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Cross, Bob, 1971-2001 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - David, Craig, 1994-2000 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - De Lorenzo, Dominick, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - De Mott, Ben, 1977-2000 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Detlefson, [Ellen] Gay, 1972-1979 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Diamond, Sig, 1994-2000 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Eisenberg, Carol, 1983-1989 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - [Elkins], Stan, 1953-2000, (5 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 4 to 8)
    - Ellis, Joe, 1988-2000 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Fields, Barbara, 1992-1993 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Fiering, Norman, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Foner, Eric, 1970-1981 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Foner, Naomi (Children's Television Workshop),1972-1977 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Gay, Peter, 1964-1996 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Goldblatt, Stuart, 1964-1976 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Greene, Jack, 1970-1983 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Gronim, Sara, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Hazzard, Shirley, 1994-2001 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Heichler, Kate, 1997-1998 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Higham, John, 1959-1999 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Hofstadter, [Richard], 1957-1995 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Hollander, Jean A., 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Howard, Chet, 1954-1992 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Hunt, Draper, 1968-1993 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Jackson, Ken, 1984-2000 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - James, Ellen Malino, 1963-1998 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Kaplanoff, Mark, 1973-1979 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Kenyon, Cecilia, 1998-2001 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      (Much of this related to a project on the writings of Cecilia Kenyon undertaken by McKitrick and others)
    - Kerber, Linda, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Klein, Herbert, 1957-1969 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Kline, M.-J., 1962-1992 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Kurtz, Steve, 1962-1996 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Leonard, Tom, 1976-1977 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Little, Lester, 1994-1999 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - McCaughey, Elizabeth, 1973-1996 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - McCaughey, Bob, 1971-2001 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - McFarland, Gerald, 1965-1978 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - McTighe, Geraldine, circa 1971-2000 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Malone, Dumas, 1959-1974 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Marcus, Joel, 1984-1986 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Markoe, Karen, 1978-1991 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Matson (Formerly Mitten), Cathy, 1982-1985 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Mattern, David, 1986-1992 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Meisinger, Diana, 1982-1984 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Merton, R.K.--Festschrift, 1971-1973 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Miles, Nelson, 1997-1999 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Miller, Wilbur R., 1976-1994 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Mitchell, Joe, circa 1996 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Morrison, Jim, 1970-1998 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Onuf, P., 1975-1978, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Paxton, Bob, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Pernick, Martin, 1972-1983 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Pole, Jack, 1973-1984 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Riesman, David, 1953-1959 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Riesman, Janet, 1982-1991 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Robarge, David, 1985-1997 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Robbins, Karen, 1985-1996 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Rosenberg, Rosalind, 1980-1999 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Ross, Kristie, 1981-1993 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Rutledge, Fleming, 1977-2000 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Saxton, Martha, 1987-1996 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Schlesinger, Steve, 1989-1993 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - St. George, Andrew, 1985-1987 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Schuyler, David, 1975-1987 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Singal, Daniel J., 1970-1984 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Sloan, Herbert, 1979-1993 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Spencer, Linda S., 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Snay, Mitchell, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Sprague, Claire, 1964-1967, Undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Stebenne, David, 1990-1996 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Straus, Michael, 1991-2000 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Swanson, Ken, 1989-1990 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Tabachnik, Leonard, 1961-1975 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Taylor, Bill, 1961-1990 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Trilling, Lionel, 1953-1975, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Vos, Frank, 1985-1996 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Waldman, Elaine, 1962-1978 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Wallace, Mike, 1972-1977, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Wilson, Jack, 1973-1978, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Winter, Ernst, 1966-1971 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Withington, Ann, 1985-1990 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Wood, Gordon, 1992-1994 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Woodward, C. V., 1954-1999 (Box 33, Folder 15 to 16)
    - Worth, Jr., William A., 1970-1976 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Young, Jessica, 1974-1988 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Zvesper, John, 1973-1984 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Subseries V.3: Personal and Family Correspondence, 1937-1946
    This subseries includes several files of "old letters" kept by McKitrick. These files include correspondence that McKitrick received from his parents, friends, and future wife during World War II.
    - Juvenilia, circa 1934-1944 (Box 23, Folder 4)